Tyler R. Phenix

Tyler Phenix's Resume Online: http://t.web.umkc.edu/trpgy5/resume/tyler_phenix.html trpgy5@umkc.edu � (816) – 977 – 5441 � 10506 Wallace Ave Kansas City, Missouri 64134

SUMMARY

Zealous and eager Desktop Technical Analyst with vast knowledge in variegated professional experiences. Consummate team player and a dexterous learner and teacher who cultivates inspiration from both peers and self. Passionate about peer-to-peer education, gaining new skills, and the development of software while also developing character.

EDUCATION

Associate in Computer Science (ACS) with an emphasis in Computer Information Systems-------December 2014 Metropolitan Community College of Kansas City - Longview - Kansas City, MO

SKILLS

Computer	Programming (C++, Java (including app development), Python, C#, etc.)			
	Database (MySQL and Oracle)			
	Big Data command prompt languages and other Apache Tools/Languages (Hadoop, Scala, Spark SQL,			٦
	Pig, etc.)			
	Web Design (e.g. JavaScript/jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, ASP.NET, PHP etc.)			
	Data and data manipulation (XML, JSON, Ajax, etc.)			
	Networking			
Personal	Oral and written communication			
	Time management, organizational, prioritization, and planning (including Agile Planning/SCRUM)			
	Decision making, analytical and problem solving			
	Creativity			
	Adaptability			
	Independent working			
	Teamwork			
Software	Adobe products and various graphic design editors (e.g. Premiere, Photoshop, Dreamweaver, Gimp etc.)			
	Microsoft Office products (e.g. Word, Excel, PowerPoint, SharePoint, etc.)			
	various Integrated Development Environment (IDE) applications (e.g. Dreamweaver, NetBeans,			
	Microsoft Visual Studios, Eclipse, etc.)			
	Command Prompt/Power Shell (Windows), Terminal (Linux and Mac)			
	Service Management and Issue Tracking Platforms (e.g. JIRA [JIRA ServiceDesk], ServiceNow			
	[ServiceCentral], BMC [Remedy])			

INTERNSHIP EXPERIENCE

Information Security Intern -------August 2017 – June 2018 Information Technology & Services | Hospitals Corporation of America – Kansas City, MO

- Protected the company from information security threats
- Created multiple information security tools that aided teammates in projects sent from corporate that affected all division employees
- Completed 3 Security Risk Assessments to ensure facilities (hospitals and ambulatory surgery centers) followed HIPAA Security Guidelines
- Assisted in hosting 4 Facility Security Committee meetings to update facility leaders on information security incidents and get feedback on information security related concerns
- Became the first SCRUM Master for our team and ultimately trained others to be SCRUM masters

Web Content Intern-----November 2015 – December 2016

National Association of Insurance Commissioners – Kansas City, MO

- Programmed innovative code that was used in production to solve ongoing challenges
- Earned 2 Star Rewards (one of the highest rewards the company offers to their employees) for outstanding work on 2 separate projects
- Kept website up to date with posting from each department for both internal and external webpages
- Promptly updated the Nation Meetings page for 2 National Meetings to ensure the correct and current information was available for leaders, staff, and those who needed to view the information

WORK EXPERIENCE

Technical Analyst------June 2018 – Present

Information Technology & Services | Hospitals Corporation of America – Kansas City, MO

- Provide support for mostly caretakers but also any other users at HCA facilities
- Manage hospital IT incidents and projects that untimely impacted patient care
- Add to the ongoing knowledge base files to make assisting users simpler for coworkers
- Train coworkers with using new ticketing management system
- Develop innovative solutions that benefited coworkers and the company by simplifying task

Service Desk Analyst II------ January 2017 – August 2017

National Association of Insurance Commissioners – Kansas City, MO

- Provided support for multiple applications that were used for businesses to submit documents to government agencies
- Created knowledge base articles to advance the knowledge of peers and future employees
- Trained interns and other coworkers with using new ticketing management system
- Educated peers on relational databases and SQL

Certified Technician-------August 2012 – November 2015

Sears Automotive – Independence, MO

- Successfully fulfilled work orders with efficiency and in accordance with Sears Automotive standards and automotive dealer specifications
- Explained vehicle diagnoses/troubleshooting steps for required repairs in a non-technical manner to service the Customer Service Advisor (CSA) and customers
- Continuously learned new technical information, advancements and techniques in formal and self-study training sessions to stay familiar with rapidly changing technology and to expand knowledge in the automotive and customer service workforce
- Inspected and tested new vehicles and recorded findings so that necessary repairs could be made

PROJECTS

My Online Resume

http://t.web.umkc.edu/trpgv5/resume/tvler_phenix.html

- Created my online resume using jQuery/JavaScript, CSS, HTML to present my talents, experience, and introduce myself
- Organized and optimized the text within my resume using jQuery/JavaScript functions and statements (e.g. I created a "boldFirstLetter" class to bold the first letter of every word within the tags, expect the words/symbols I specified, instead of manually changing the font-weight of each letter)
- Constructed my website to be responsive (i.e. function properly and look similar on any device)

Budget Watch App

https://github.com/typ64/449 project

- Designed a Java based Android mobile application to help users keep track of what they buy while shopping to help them stay on budget
- Implemented efficient functions to keep a dynamic running total to make the app more user friendly and increase efficiency

• Demonstrated good coding practices by keeping my business logic code separate from my user interface [UI] code and refactoring functions that lacked efficiency

Big Data Project

https://github.com/typ64/bigdata/

- Extracted almost 2000 tweets based on the keyword "trump" and performed over 20 queries on the data to analyze it and find certain trends
- Produced concise quires to best obtain the results needed and extracted the output to a comma-separated values (CSV) file for simpler analysis